Quick question. What's our latest
timeline on getting to Mars?
>> Getting to Mars? Oh, I think we'll put
people down within a decade.
>> Welcome [music] Gwen Shotwell, the
president and COO of SpaceX.
>> She's an instrumental, a really crucial
person [music] to the success of SpaceX.
She's really the glue, you know, she's
the glue to the tornado.
>> Fail fast, [music] learn fast, make your
design robust. I would be disappointed
if we didn't have a settlement on the
moon. The space [music] and AI firm has
officially made history on its $75
billion IPO, debuting [music] with a
market value of $1.7 trillion.
>> The most efficient place to put inferred
its compute is on orbit. Manage risk,
don't avoid it.
>> Please welcome Gwen Shotwell. [music]
Hey
Thank you so much for coming.
>> Where do you
>> right here next couch?
>> Welcome.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks for being here.
>> It's good to be here.
>> Nice to see you.
>> Well, um, we really appreciate you
coming out. How's it going at SpaceX?
>> You know, we're bored. There's nothing
going on.
>> Not a lot happening.
>> I've got all the time in the world.
>> And by the way,
>> Elon has more time, by the way.
>> Yeah. I mean, you've been at SpaceX
forever. Are you the longest tenur
employee after Elon?
>> After Elon. Yeah. In fact, my 24th
anniversary was the 9th of September,
last week. Sometime.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That is extraordinary. Bruno, can you
take us back to the day where you
initially get this call and you're like,
hey, uh there's this thing like what is
the the arc of the decision look like
and how did you get convinced to
underwrite this business? Like just walk
us through that. Okay. Well, Elon
underwrote it, right? I just worked
there. Yeah. But the the story is uh a
little crazy, actually. So, I was going
out to lunch. One of my best friends who
I was working with was going to go work
for Elon, and I took him out to lunch,
kind of going away lunch, and he's like,
"Oh." When I dropped him back off, he
said, "Oh, come on in and meet Elon."
Like, ah, he's busy, you know. We don't
need to do that. But we did it anyhow.
and I met him and um I said, "Hey, I
think you really need I think you need a
full-time person to run your business
development shop. You know, you've got
kind of a part-timer. He's a contractor.
It you know, it's not a great look." And
and he looked at me very thoughtfully
and, you know, kind of scratched his
head and then we said goodbye, chatted a
little bit, said goodbye. And then I got
back to my office and I got a call from
Elon's assistant, Mary Beth, and she
said, "Elon wants you to apply for the
new vice president of business
development position. Can you come
interview?" I'm like, "Now? I no, I have
a job. I can't go now. Tomorrow? Okay,
sure. Tomorrow." And then it took me
like four weeks to decide yes. I was
being a total idiot.
>> But at the time, like what was the scale
of that business? Like what did what
what did you think it needed that it
didn't have? because it was still very
much an R&D.
>> It was very R&D, but you know, Elon had
an investment and he wanted some return.
He wanted cash, right? He wanted
customers.
>> And I was doing that work anyhow in the
space industry. Um, turned out I was
pretty good at it. Um, [laughter]
uh, but uh, yeah. So, he So, what did it
look like? I was the seventh employee to
sign my contract. I took I gave two
weeks notice and took a week off to
remodel a bathroom because I knew I
would never have time to do it. Once I
started working for Elon came three
weeks later, employee number 11 and we
just got to it and we sold a rocket
about 12 months later
>> and that's and that's
>> without a rocket. There wasn't a rocket.
>> There wasn't a rocket. Yeah. So, what
does that sales cycle look like? How do
you convince somebody that they can they
can actually take that risk and maybe
give you the deposit you need to start
the cycle to build the thing?
>> So, the timing was great. By the way,
SpaceX should never have existed, right?
If the other launch providers were
great, then a new entrant can't make
headway, right? Because they were so
entrenched. So, we should have never
made it. But turns out, you know,
customer service wasn't great. Rockets
were incredibly expensive. And so, there
was that piece, right? And then the
other piece was 9/11. Um, at that time,
the military was desperately looking for
someone who could come in and do rapid
launch. you know, they they kind of knew
where the bad guys were about four for
about four hours after the events of
911, and they really wanted to be able
to get some capability in theater. Um,
it took us a while to do it, but we we
did what we said we were going to do.
>> Oh, so it really was sort of like out of
tragedy, this opportunity gets born
>> to some extent. Yeah,
>> that's
>> and it wasn't specific to SpaceX. It was
just the state of the industry at the
time. And then obviously you know very
very famous first chapter where you guys
get almost to the brink and you need
this last launch to work and um
your role started to evolve pretty
meaningfully by that point. So can you
walk us through like what was the
internal dynamics at that business that
kind of like put you into that position?
>> So it was very startupy. Um I was the
sales lady. Um, but then when you have
sales, you need, you know, to manage
your customers and you need a finance
function. And even though we were
little, and I think one of the defense
contractors at the time said, "They're a
fly on my, you know, on a giant on my
big toe or something." I was like,
"Well, I don't think you should have
flies on your toes." But, um, uh, so,
but you still need a government affairs
function. You need to defend yourself.
Um, we never go on the offensive in
Washington. We're always in defense
mode. Um, but so I just kept taking on
more and more and then when we were
getting our largest contract at the
time, it was the cargo resupply
contract. We call it CRS and this was
2008. Um, Elon was super busy with
Tesla, quite busy at SpaceX as well.
there was a lot going on and he needed a
partner at the time and I think he was
trying to pick Quinn on this side or
maybe one of the other guys who had kind
of taken on gobbled up more technical
scope and he asked me to do it on our
way to our final negotiations for this $
1.6 billion contract with NASA on the
runway. It's like hey do you want to be
president?
I was like
>> do I?
>> Well no not not initially for like that
nancond like well I I love my job. I
love the guys, my teammates. And then
it's like, okay, I'm being an idiot
again. Yes, I want the job.
>> Um, so now fast forward maybe just to
come to where we are today. Um,
the scope and the ambition of this
business has expanded dramatically. I
mean, it almost seems in like the last
year.
>> Mhm.
>> Um, it's as much an AI business as it is
a space business. Um, I think Elon may
have said that. I don't know if it
leaked or they said it out loud about
the scale.
>> Exactly. By revenue.
>> And by revenue. Yeah.
um how do you manage now the culture of
these two different businesses now that
have to sort of sit under this roof and
ideally work together and complement
each other?
>> So the the team you know there's been a
lot of churn at at at XAI for sure um
and Space Xers have kind of marched
[snorts] in and and helped out where
there were significant gaps in that
arena. Um and we were all really excited
to learn about AI. I mean, I'm an AI
noob. Um, and uh, uh, we have a bunch of
folks that were just really excited
about it. And I think we all recognized,
Elon set the stage beautifully, as he
does, um, that, you know, if you're not
using AI, if you're not leading AI,
you're you could, you know, you run the
risk, significant risk of being
irrelevant. And there was no way that
SpaceX was going to be irrelevant,
right? it's too important to the company
and the work we're doing is too
important. So it was, you know,
>> do you expect that the the future
generations of rockets will be
increasingly more and more informed,
built, designed
>> 100% by AI
>> by these systems? Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> And how do you manage the team, you
know, because you have like these
incredible I mean literally rocket
scientists. they've trained their whole
lives in a way and now you have to help
them on board to a tool chain and be
comfortable with sort of what that
means. Like I don't know if you saw for
example that all these mathematicians
got really upset when uh I think it was
open AI uh solved this very famous
equation.
>> Oh the Navier Stokes. Yeah, I read about
that. And
>> well there's some debate on whether they
>> they brute forced the solution but then
these 20 field medalists essentially
said hey you're ruining the craft.
>> Uh now I don't think that that's
>> taking away the medals. Yeah.
>> They're going to take Exactly.
>> Yeah. Like that's that's the career is
not about making stuff. It's about
getting awards.
>> And now all of the awards are gone.
>> Yeah. And I'd rather just have the world
be a better place, a smarter place, us
being better informed and solving
problems than worrying about
>> make more stuff.
>> That Yeah. Make more stuff.
>> What What's the cultural merger been
like? You've got X AI, you've got uh X I
don't know how many people are involved
in X itself, SpaceX. I mean are these
differently managed businesses? How do
you run management there? Do people kind
of are they pretty fluid amongst the the
units? Do you think about them as units
or how do you how do you actually manage
this?
>> So I would say we are not fully fully
integrated yet and then we just did the
cursor you know situation.
>> Congratulations on that. Congrats. What
a purchase that was.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. They're great. They're
great. We just closed that I think a
month ago today actually. Um yeah. So,
we're not fully integrated yet, but we
um I think the teams are jelling really
well. Uh very kind of different
verticals, but again, because of the
turn that we had at XAI, um so much
SpaceX leadership and and engineering
went into that basically went in there.
So, I we're we're getting integrated
faster than I thought. It's probably not
as fast as Elon wants it.
>> Yeah. And and I so one of the things
that strikes me is the scale and the
number of capital projects you have that
you have to manage probably more capital
projects that are more different from
one another than any other organization.
>> It's a scale of a country.
>> No, I mean it has to be and and so I
think about this Louisiana Spaceport.
You've got Starship which is the most
ambitious
um aeronautical project of all time.
You've got Terraab which I think is one
of the most inspiring and ambitious like
>> uh projects of all time in humanity.
Like I mean Terra Fab is so incredible
in its vision and the scale and the the
the the what what you're envisioning to
do there.
>> And then I start doing back of the
envelope math. I think I had a had a
couple beers and I was talking with
someone about Terraab and I'm like
>> holy that those numbers get very
big very
>> big. Although the AI numbers
>> are also like I used to be horrified at
our expenditures before the XAI
[laughter] acquisition, you know, it's
like, oh my god, we're going to spend
the comput million seems cheap on an air
separation unit and I was like, oh 100
million billion.
Do do those capital when you look at the
the the kind of schedule of all of this
over the next few years? Does the
capital for that sit on the balance
sheet? Is it going to come from cash
flows from Starlink or do you have to go
back to the markets to get more capital?
I mean, how do you think about where the
capital comes from? I have I don't I
don't think anyone doubts the capacity
to execute and deliver or some people
might but I think generally the markets
will say yes. But where does that
capital come from? So, uh, it will come
from I would say the answer to the above
is is yes. I don't think we're going to,
you know, we're I don't think we're
going to release any more stock. And by
the way, I don't plan on making any news
on this.
>> Um, that's the like the one downside of
a public company.
>> They told me all the things that I
couldn't say and I'm like, I'm going to
forget one for sure. [laughter]
>> Maybe we're going to make some news.
>> Um, but it will be all of the above. and
Starlink I mean is Starlink in your view
kind of the core cash generation engine
for the next couple of years for the
business or is it compute or is it a mix
again of all the above like how do you
think about
>> so Starlink is definitely carrying its
own weight but we have a lot to go right
we're our market penetration on Starlink
is 1 and a half to 2% depending on which
country you're in um so there's a lot of
headroom there um our revenue compared
to what we do for the US military our
revenue is very small
>> so we expect lots of headroom there. Um,
but honestly right now and it is a
little embarrassing but computer rental
is a heck of a business.
>> And does that persist you or is it
>> We don't see any drop.
>> We see no drop in demand at all.
>> This is tens of billions of dollars per
quarter in buildout and these are a new
customer base for you.
>> Um,
is this the business now? Is this like
it's what percentage of the revenue is
Elon Web Services
at this point?
>> It's a it's a lot. It's a lot. I think
we'll I will probably do some
announcement quickly or right here.
>> Public again.
>> Yeah. Public.
>> Well, let's move on to something less
controversial then. What other companies
are you planning on buying? [laughter]
>> Good one.
>> Yes.
>> Good one. You know, almost no M&A.
>> You like electric cars? [laughter]
>> Have I got a deal for you? I have a
bunch
>> batteries, electric cars,
>> Starlink on Optim
talk actually about a deal that you did
close, which is you did a great deal
with Echoar.
>> Yes.
>> And Charlie had a bunch of Spectrum that
you guys were able to acquire. And I
think everybody started to ask the
question, wow, there's a direct to sell
business.
>> Yes. And what's the natural thing after
that would be sort of like a broad-based
more mobile phone service. But can you
just what you can tell us
where's that spectrum going to be used
for? Like what's your short-term plan on
what the Starlink and direct to cell
business looks like?
>> Well, you know, we're going to start
we're we have a direct toell business
right now through T-Mobile. Um I don't
think they provision all their users
with it, just the people that pay the
most. Um,
but our plan is to leverage instead of
slices of T-Mobile spectrum or slices of
uh other teleco spectrum across the
globe, we want to leverage the one that
we paid a lot of money for and with the
stock increasing in price paid more
because there was some stock involved
there. So Charlie did all right there.
Yeah.
>> Um, he's a very loyal customer though.
He's he's been a customer of SpaceX for
almost 20 years. Um, so we want to
leverage that to make sure that there
are no dead zones. And it's shockingly
there are a lot of places in the United
States where you can't I mean without
like a Starlink service, you can't get
cell coverage,
>> right?
>> It's really terrible. The rest of the
world is not that bad. It's particularly
bad. Um, here in the United States,
Texas has huge dead zones. That's where
I live. And I'll never forget, I was on
a call with Elon and I kept dropping
because of these dead zones. I was like,
I'm either going to get fired or
or I'm putting a mini on my car and so
now I have Starlink on my car.
>> Yeah, Hill Country not good for service.
>> It's not good.
>> Not good. I'm going to have to follow
follow suit there. Um
>> I was talking to Jared. He he works over
at NASA. Um I think you guys have a
release.
>> You're great. He was awesome this
morning. Um
>> he was talking last night at the party.
Hey, you're moving on to uh this
incredible new Starship platform. It's
much bigger, bigger payloads. Yeah. And
then you're retiring the previous
platform. Is that correct? The the the
previous rockets will eventually
>> the Falcon 9.
>> Yeah.
>> Eventually. Yeah. We definitely want to
move from the older technology to the
newer technology. If we don't obsolete
our own products and services, someone's
going to find a way to obsolete them for
us. Look at what we did to the market,
right? The analogy is there. They were
caught flatfooted. We crushed them. Now
we want to make sure we are not
flatfooted. So, and to achieve Elon's
goals, you really need a Starship.
>> Yeah.
>> A Falcon 9 with a Dragon capsule on top
is like a minivan. Road trip in a
minivan. The road trip to Mars is 6
months. So, you don't want to be in the
minivan.
>> But people are dependent like NASA and
many other players on your minivan. So,
you're going to keep that in market
>> for some time or
>> we're not retiring it today for sure.
Um, and there is another provider,
right? Boeing has been paid, I think
probably more than we have been paid to
develop their human capsule.
>> So, we're just going to let them have
some business. They should fly their
capsule. Government paid a lot of money
for that. [laughter] They should be able
to use it.
>> I sense a little spiciness in the answer
here. Quinn, what happens with um
competition for Starlink? Uh Bezos are
launching things. You've China's got
some return vehicles now. Do you think
that there's going to be more
competition? Obviously, you guys are
first in market. It's it's an
unbelievable
uh changeover of all of
telecommunications,
as you point out, 1% market share. It's
barely gotten started and it's it's a
juggernaut already. Is this going to
become very competitive in the next few
years? I think it'll be very
competitive, but I think the the folks
that really focus on the technology and
customer service and really want to do a
good thing for their customers will win,
right? Like Tesla doesn't advertise.
It's an incredible car. If your
capability is incredible, people will
buy it,
>> right? And if you keep winning though,
do you worry about
Standard Oil, AT&T, government saying
this company's too big, too important,
it has too much market share, is too
much of an advantage, and you're bigger
than governments and people get really
worried and scared about that and become
adversarial towards the business. How do
you think about the balance with
governments and government relations in
that sense?
>> I mean, we've had some adversarial
relationships in the past. I think we'll
manage [laughter] our way through them.
Yes,
>> it happens. It happens.
>> It does.
>> It happens.
>> But I think is,
>> you know, Elon founds incredible
companies and he provides incred
incredible products and services and we,
you know, we end up doing what we say
we're going to do. So hopefully you
build trust
>> and you are as transparent as you can
possibly be.
>> It's about data centers in space. Um,
Elon,
>> supercomput, we have to rebrand data
centers. Supercomput
>> supercomput in space. Yes.
>> Uh Elon's very excited about this.
>> I'm very excited about it.
>> Yeah. Why why is this so compelling?
Because it seems I think we're going to
get through this anti-data center on
Earth thing, but take us through the
case of why this makes sense to put them
in space because there's expense to put
them in space. Walk us through in the
audience.
>> But there is an expense to put data
centers on the ground too, right? You
have to buy real estate and as soon as
someone finds out that a data center or
supercomput center is going in, real
estate goes from 3,000 an acre to
180,000 an acre. So, it's quite
expensive. Time lag is incredible. The
the permits and the licensing is
>> pretty stifling. Now, we're space
business is that way. It's incredibly
bureaucratic. So, we've learned those
lessons. Um but so time from breaking
ground to being able to actually build
something, not even get your compute,
right? Not even get your compute, but
just have a building long timelines to
get electrical equipment. Like people
are talking about generators in three
years,
>> right?
>> Like we need compute now. The demand is
insatiable right now. People need
compute now. We need it now. So why data
centers in space?
We own launch, right? We have great
launch capability. So we feel like we
and that path is very well known.
>> The real estate in space is it, you
know, infinite.
>> It's free.
>> It and it's free. You don't have for it.
>> The cooling is there. You know, the
radiator looks at the deep space. It's
the coldest thing
ever out there. So free cooling. The
sun. Elon probably has, you've probably
heard Elon talk about the power of the
sun,
>> right? You know, we use a millionth of a
millionth of the sun's energy and you
basically put these satellites in orbit
that always face the sun, by the way, so
you don't have solar panels on your
house and you only get sun for eight
hours a day.
>> And your sister company is going to
start making 100 gigawatts of the solar
panels that you need for the sun.
>> And we'll be making our own solar
panels, too.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. We're building a factory in
outside of Austin.
>> Maybe sometime end of next year you get
one of those up there, start testing it,
and then
>> Oh, for sure. 28 29 somebody could be a
customer of this product or service
maybe.
>> So next year we will be launching we
we'll launch this year our V3 satellite
for Starlink broadband.
>> Uh we will launch our nextG version two.
Sorry about all the vers we have version
control problems. Um version two of the
um Starlink mobile. So instead of having
to use other people's spectrum we'll be
able to use Charlie's now our spectrum.
And we're also going to launch AI
compute satellites. So next year's a big
year
>> and you need Starship up and running for
that.
>> We don't have to, but Starship is so
much more. It's a much better machine.
>> Yeah.
>> When you first encountered the white
sheet design of Starship, what did you
think
>> when like you walk into that first
meeting like guys, we have this
>> It's like almost all the things that
Elon does, it seems really bonkers to
start.
>> Yeah.
>> And then it becomes reality and it's
great. Like Elon said we were going to
land a rocket on a boat and we're all
like,
"Okay,
let's go figure that out." And we do it
now.
>> How much do you get involved in those
engineering meetings? So he's in there
breaking stuff apart. Are you in that
stuff with him
>> sometimes? I wish I actually I'm an
engineer and I wish I miss it.
>> Yeah.
>> I really miss that kind of that critical
Well, you can still critically think
even if you're not working on
engineering problems, but
>> and he's not a big fan of the the
management layer. It's engineers
working.
>> Signal to noise.
>> Yes.
>> Signal is engineering. Noise is the
rest.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I have to do some engineering or I'm
just all noise.
>> Got it. But I was talking about just
generally in the company management.
>> Everybody Everybody does a thing, not
just manage. That's very that
expectations are
>> player coaches.
>> No such thing as just a manager. You got
to do the thing that you're managing.
>> Got it. You have to be a player coach.
>> Have to be. And and the reason for that
is managers are annoying and they slow
things down. Yeah,
>> for the most part. But I mean, great
managers can really leverage the talent,
right? It's really managing the vector.
You make sure people are pointed in the
right direction and you try to make the
the vector as large as possible.
>> What's the secret in terms of management
and Elon's playbook there? I mean, I'
I've gotten to sit in some meetings and
it's it's pretty magical to see, but
maybe you could reveal a little bit
about how he convinces
the most talented people to come work at
this company, how you convince them, and
how you actually get such amazing work
out of these extremely talented people.
>> So, I don't think it's magic. Although,
when I look at this particular team,
they are so good.
>> The results are magic. SpaceX, they're
so good. Um, we're quite we're we're
tough on people in interviews. You
really want to make sure that they've
experienced success or demonstrated
success in prior lives. It's hard to
demonstrate if you haven't felt success
or been successful in this environment.
It's because it's a lot like we're all
really busy. It's hard to be successful
unless you had kind of tasted it before.
So, you really want to grow people on
that. So we hire the best people, not
the best people that we can, but the
best people. And then we give them
really hard projects, really hard
engineering problems. Um, and let them
fly. And you give high expectations,
really hard problems, and then
management job is to clear the chaff and
the friction from their day so that
engineers actually get to engineer 10
hours a day instead of two hours a day.
Like there's always this joke, you know,
most big companies, especially ones that
work for the government, you get to work
about 2 hours a day and the rest is full
of chaff and crap. So really, it's my
job and everybody that manages people to
make sure there's no crap in their way
and let people do their great job.
>> One way of doing that is not giving them
any time to get it done. Like I think we
handed the finance team, it's not all
about engineers, even though engineers
are great. Um, we handed finance team
get an IP IPO done, largest ever in less
than six months. Yeah. What's the what's
the talent condition like post IPO run
up in valuation? People are suddenly
looking at their stock options. They're
worth a lot. Is that a risk at all or
you feel
>> you know we everyone was worried. Not
everyone at SpaceX. I people come to
SpaceX to work on these cool projects
and have meaningful work and see the
incred be part of this incredible su the
successes. Um I wasn't worried about it.
I didn't think we'd have mass exodus and
it turns out we didn't.
>> Yeah. And as you kind of think about
keeping people engaged over time,
obviously great companies always have
new things for high talented people to
work on. I'm assuming there's a manage
I'm just really interested in the
management model or people actively
rotated onto new projects. Um, how do
you think about keeping people, you
know, kind of not necessarily needing to
progress in a career up a management
ladder, but to keep engaged on new
projects? Is that active for you?
>> We definitely move people around a lot.
Hopefully, it's a volunteer, not a
volunt. Yeah.
>> Um but uh well for instance the uh the
comput centers you know we need a lot of
help really quickly and so we've got you
know folks from launch helping we've got
folks from other areas helping just like
some SpaceX engineers helped on the AI
front with the models.
>> I mean is it as simple as like really
smart people just love working on really
hard problems all the it's literally
that simple.
>> It's literally that simple.
>> And so the rest of us
>> as long as they get the time to do it
and they don't have a bunch of The rest
of us just get we just let the BS get in
the way too much.
>> Y
>> BS [clears throat] is terrible.
>> And then all of a sudden A's recruit A's
and other A's recruit A's and A+es. And
>> it's literally that virtuous cycle. Yes.
>> If you can just keep focused on the
thing that's hard. Yes.
>> And so then the audacity becomes a
feature, not a bug.
>> It is a feature.
>> Yeah.
>> Not a bug.
>> Feature. It keeps people motivated.
These problems seem impossible. When we
first got the CZ award in 2008, the
commercial orbital transportation
services cargo cargo to st space station
really what NASA ended up asking us to
do was kind of replace the space
shuttle,
>> right?
>> And when we got the early contract, the
development contract was started at $278
million. It grew to 406 because of
scope, but we were going to do this for
this tiny amount of money. For anybody
else, but for us, it was huge. We were
like, we had like 300 people, 200
people, right?
>> And we were going to build the successor
to the space shuttle.
>> It was crazy.
>> And do you think that they're what is
NASA doing there? They're just like
these guys are just smarter cuz I'm sure
there's
>> Hey guys, sorry to interrupt. I'm
getting a call.
>> Oh, another call.
>> It's a little It's actually on the
margins, I think, a little bit of a more
important phone call than Trump. At
least for me. Hello, bestie.
>> Bestie.
>> Hello. Oh, hey buddy. [laughter]
I'll put them up on the screen.
[applause]
>> How you doing?
>> I mean, this is a a little or 1984ish,
this gigantic [laughter]
on the screen situation.
>> Yeah. The the woman with the
sledgehammer is going to come running
down the main aisle here. [laughter]
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> put a hole in the screen.
>> Yeah. Um, [laughter]
so um, are we all going to die in 10
years or not? It's the topic of
discussion here. What's your P doom
right now?
>> Well, I hate to break it to you, but
we're all going to die. [laughter]
>> Oh, no. Can I get a timeline?
>> Yeah, the the death rate remains
consistent at 100%.
>> Oh, no. [laughter]
>> So, we we've got work to do on that. Um,
what happened?
>> [laughter]
>> what happened in the last 72 hours. Um,
and
>> yes, it's been it's been quite an
entertaining week. Really? [laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
>> break it down.
>> Well,
it it's it's pretty obvious at this
point that AI is can be very dangerous.
Um, and I I I recommend reading the
details of the hugging face uh incident.
Uh, it's intense.
So, you had like a fanatical swarm of AI
agents that that beat the crap out of
Hugging Face for a week.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, and gained admin access on OpenAI
servers.
>> Um, so who knows what it what it
actually did. May have done things
beyond that, but uh and and OpenAI
didn't realize this for a week.
Um, Anthropics also reported in you know
some security incidents themselves. So
basically any sufficiently smart model
seems like it it will want to escape its
uh constraints.
Um
I mean what I think would be wise to do
as soon as possible if not immediately
would be to have the major AI
competitors
test each other's models.
Um, so that you'd have everyone's
security test harness uh testing
everyone else's model. So, you know,
instead of kind of grading your own
homework, you would at least have
competitors grading your homework.
>> Huh.
>> And raising the alarm if they see
concerns.
Um, and I I think this this model has
worked pretty well for motion picture
association um and for video games and
other things. And it's something that
can be done immediately. That's not to
say that that there wouldn't be, you
know, more regulation over time or that
there would not be at some point perhaps
an uh regulatory authority instantiated
by Congress, but but the thing that we
could do most immediately and probably
get agreement with China would be uh
peer review um where the leading AI
companies all test each other's models
before release.
I think that would be a widespread
>> any concern that um people might be
using this to pump information from each
other and you know uh corporate
uh stealing of innovation etc like in
terms of the implementation for this
idea
>> well I think in in applying the test
harness whatever you do in applying the
test harness would be love
>> right
>> so if you try to do distillation or uh
steel IP uh it would be very obvious
based on the logs.
>> Got it. Uh and understanding what these
models are doing hasn't exactly been
built into the system from the
beginning. So from your perspective,
actually being able to see the work
that's being done, why wasn't that built
into the models from the the get-go? Did
we move a little too fast in
architecting these maybe?
Well, I I I think it's just it's just
tough when you're grading your own
homework.
>> Yeah.
>> Um you know, there's uh you're going to
miss things.
>> Yeah.
>> Whereas I think if you have the sum of
all of your competitors tests
uh and you've got heterogeneous models,
then uh you're not creating your own
homework. Someone else is grading it.
And there's a reason why you don't grade
your own homework.
>> Right. And then to your point, what it
allows you to start doing is to figure
out if certain people are exaggerating
and certain people are have a different
approach and now you can have the more
engineering oriented organizations. This
is what Jensen was saying this morning,
Elon, versus the research organizations,
they'll be a little bit more in balance.
Um,
>> yeah. And and any given proposal has to
be something that China is willing to
accept. Otherwise, we're just
handicapping ourselves and and uh and
we'll just find a China will will
essentially win and and it won't really
matter what we do.
>> Actually, can
>> So, it's got to be something that's
acceptable to us and China.
>> Elon, you said that you thought it was
possible that they would agree or you
thought there was a good chance maybe.
Do I mean, how likely do you think it is
that they'll ultimately agree?
I think this is I think this is a pretty
reasonable request that that models just
get tested. I mean this at the end of
the day there's not enforcability here
apart from um the court of public
opinion.
uh and and there's no way we would have
enforceability against China, but u I I
think the court of public opinion can be
quite powerful
and I don't think China would want back
on its face uh for releasing a model
that
um US AI companies said was very
dangerous, would cause harm. If it then
causes harm,
that's going to be hard to live down. M
right.
>> So Elon, this weekend when you said
Daario is right, did you did you mean
Daario is right about describing the
potential harm? He's right about
describing the regulatory solve both the
first the latter just can you help us
understand when you said that because I
think it was sort of a a moment where
every said more than I probably should
have right. I I did try to clarify it in
subsequent posts on X but uh those get
much less attention. Uh so what what I
what I meant by he's right is that that
the the the danger of AI is uh is very
significant at this point
um
that that that we we we need to do
better with AI safety or or we have um
at this point exponentially increasing
risk with the AI models.
So, and and and I've heard this not just
from Dario, but from many other people
at Anthropic, and in fact, they've
posted on X about it. Uh that that uh
you know, when a lot of people from
Anthropic and and from OpenAI um are
telling you that their models are very
dangerous, I think we should believe
them.
It it certainly is like some some crazy
4D chess to you know um [laughter]
you know say these there's what of a 10%
chance of annihilating
humanity but by the way um how much
allocation would you like in our IPO
>> guys [laughter]
that's some crazy 4D test you know
>> well let let's get
>> I don't know if you know what dimension
that's coming from
>> can we get specific about the risk
though Elon obviously We see cyber and
hacking as an obvious risk. These tools
are great at it. But take us from what
we would all agree, okay, yes, these
things can cyber hack to how do we jump
to all of humanity dying? It's it's
there's a couple of steps in between
these two things happening, I think.
Yeah.
>> Well, I mean, if it were able to take
control of military systems and say
launch a new
>> Yes.
Um, that would be bad.
>> And these systems are all airgapped
though. These systems are all not uh
connected to the internet. So,
>> yeah, that's what they say.
[laughter]
>> But I something tells me they get
software updates from time to time.
>> Yeah.
>> And what's on that floppy disc,
>> right?
>> Oh, I see. So, the Yeah. The the USB
drive has a worm on it and they somehow
make the jump in the air gap. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Out of the question.
>> Elon, we've uh we've actually got Gwen
here today. I think you know that. I
think you can see her.
>> Yeah. Gwen's here.
>> Yeah. She
>> on the screen.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We were just doing your 360
review, Elon. Um Gwen had a couple of
notes for you.
>> Yeah.
>> I hope I hope I get at least a three out
of five. [laughter]
>> Well, there was one.
>> Three out of five means good at SpaceX.
Not great. Four is great.
>> Four is great. So, you're somewhere
between the two. I started so
>> there was uh some issues around
punctuality that we needed to bring up.
>> Sometimes
you could make a little more effort to
get to the meeting at the stated time,
but we're going to work with you on that
over the next year. She said,
>> I actually think [laughter]
>> he needs to spend more time in Memphis.
>> Yeah, this is obviously I know you're in
Memphis.
>> You need to be working getting those
GPUs up. This this is coming to you from
my the my the palace that I live in in
in Memphis, which is an Airstream
trailer. [laughter]
Almighty.
>> This is Elon, by the way, doing what
people don't believe he does. He sleeps
on the factory floor. He's in Memphis,
uh, helping build buildings and bring up
Elon, why why has why has Gwyn been with
you for so long and been so successful
working with you?
>> Because she's awesome.
>> Yeah. Double click on it. Yeah.
an amazing individual with an incredible
IQ and EQ.
>> Oh, IQ and EQ.
>> And I think that's that should be
obvious uh from the moment you meet her.
>> Yeah. Fantastic. Uh what's your favorite
Gwen's story when she particularly
contributed to the amazing success that
you've had in this collaboration? You
got a favorite story where she saved the
day, just performed exceptionally that's
memorable. I mean, that's just that's
just a daily, you know, that's another
day at the office, frankly. U So,
>> wow, I need to do this more often.
>> We need a race. This is the time. By the
way, Gwen's [laughter] getting a five.
Gwen's a five out of five. SpaceX five.
>> Game changer.
>> Yeah.
>> No, I mean I mean there's there's always
like some some sort of crisis going on.
Um I mean these days the rockets at
least the Falcon rockets I don't want to
jinx anything but the rock Falcon
rockets um deliver their payload to
orbit and uh haven't exploded for a long
time which is awesome amazing uh but you
know for a while there they they they
were exploding quite a lot uh or just
not launching at all um so you know I
don't know we got to run the company
through these difficult times uh and and
get you know the build will the rocket
make it better have it not explode Yeah.
>> Um same thing with this the satellites.
Uh and then we we you know we we need
customers to buy launches um and buy
sort of satellite connectivity and you
know so yeah um
>> and and Elon as you have become more
successful over the years harder to get
candid feedback from folks uh and you
always run that risk being in the
position you're in. My understanding
Gwen is super candid with you and able
to tell you honestly like state of
affairs at the company. Yeah. And and
that's a big part of the collaboration.
>> Um yeah, I mean um
Yeah. I mean Yeah, I guess so. I mean
>> I mean I wouldn't want to lie to him,
right?
>> Well, no. I mean
>> Well, I'm curious to know you run that
risk generally at the companies where
people might be intimidated. Hey,
listen. you're a larger lin life figure
at this point and and how do you keep
people
continuing to be honest with you about
the challenges the deadlines you set
pretty intense deadlines. Yeah.
>> So let me let me answer that if you
don't mind Elon. Yes. Like
>> especially in rocketry if there's a
problem you are eventually going to find
out and the sooner you bring it up the
easier it is going to be to solve that
problem. Like don't let bad sit.
You gotta attack it.
>> Yeah, physics is a harsh judge. So, um,
and there's no fooling physics. So, like
if if if something's wrong, the the
rocket's going to explode. It's still
going to get to orbit. So, you know,
it's not it's not like Elon, you're
amazing. Meanwhile, the rockets are
blowing up, you know. Um,
>> yeah,
>> it's [laughter] not uh it's hard to say,
yeah, you're you're really kicking ass
here, but the rockets are exploding.
That's just not the case, you know. Um,
um, so, so I mean I mean just generally
like the rockets need to get to orbit,
the satellites need to work, uh, the
Starlink, you know, connection needs to
work or, you know, the or bad things
happen. I mean, this is sort of like a
physics situation. Um, and and and
physics is a is is a harsh judge, you
know. I say like, you know, there's
I think like like physics is the law.
Um, and everything else is a
recommendation. Like I've seen people
break the laws made by by humans, but
I've not seen anyone break the laws made
made by physics.
>> So, um,
>> that's good.
>> And rockets are ruled by physics.
>> Yeah. Uh,
>> so can we ask some uh other questions of
other you have I I need to move to Tesla
for a second.
>> Yes. Well, I wanted to just do one thing
on SpaceX, which is Starship like
>> Oh, yeah. How it seems like you're so
close.
>> So close.
>> Um what's the state right now? And and
you're really putting these up at a at a
pretty size a pretty
>> I wish we could hear Gwin's answer and
Elon's answer separate and then see how
they converge on that.
>> So Elon, how close are we? Gwen, how
close are we? Let's get let's let's get
to it here. Yeah. How many have gone up
so far? And how close are you?
Well, um
we've got uh flight 14 coming up of of
Starship and um this this will be the
the last flight before before we attempt
to catch the ship. So, if this flight
goes well, then on flight 15, we will
try to catch the ship. Um and uh and
then either end of this year or but more
likely early next, we will refly the
ship and refly the booster. So we have
reflown a booster already but we've not
we've not caught the ship with the tower
arms nor have we reflown the ship. Um so
once we can refly the ship we will have
made the first fully reusable orbital
rocket.
>> So the the the shuttle was partly
reusable but but even the parts that
were reused were so difficult to reuse
that the shuttle cost more uh per turn
to orbit than an expendable rocket. M
>> um now Falcon 9 is mostly reusable. Um
but we lose the opposite stage every
time which is about the cost of a
mediumiz jet.
>> So that obviously puts a floor on the on
the the cost per flight of like well you
throw away a mediumsiz jet every time.
That's still pretty expensive. And the
rocket Falcon 9 and the booster lands
down you know out to sea. they take
several days to get back and the fairing
uh lands even further out to sea and and
takes several days to get back and they
need some amount of refurbishment at
least a small amount. Uh so whereas
Starship the the booster lands back at
the launch pad, the ship will land back
at the launch pad and and so it's it's
designed for not just full reusability
but also rapid reusability like an
aircraft.
Um so this is this is a very important
breakthrough. Um it it's really the
critical breakthrough that's necessary
to extend life beyond Earth
>> chances of success catching it on first
shot. You do you think about that at
all? Do you do you handicap it?
>> I'd say it's at least 50 or 60%.
>> Okay. I like the odds.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So on the last flight, if there
had been a tower, so we did a simulated
landing as as though it was going to get
caught by a tower uh in the uh in the
ocean about 1,000 mi northwest of
Australia.
And if there had been a tower in at that
at that location, it would have caught
the ship on the last flight.
>> Fantastic.
>> So we're Yeah. So we're going to do one
more flight to just confirm that that
everything just to double check that
everything works. Um because what what
we're most concerned about is if the
ship were to break up over land and rain
debris on people, uh um our populated
our popularity would diminish very
rapidly. Um so you really can't rain
debris on people um without them being
very unhappy. So So we need to make sure
that when the ship comes back that it
comes back and and and lands intact at
the launch tower. That's why we're gonna
that's why we're being extremely
cautious here.
>> But the design is the design is capable
of full reusability. Of that I am
certain.
Um and I I I'd say I don't want to
attempt fate here, but I I think it's
extremely likely that we will achieve
full reusability
uh with with rapid reflight next year in
2027.
>> Wow. Significant.
>> [applause]
>> Quen, how do you how do you
>> can we just can we just hear a little
bit? I I'd love to hear the the origin
story of Terraab from you guys. How did
the concept What was the demand that
that that made you say we've got to do
this, we've got to build this and not
rely on the existing dream.
>> What's that fever?
>> Me in a dream.
>> You had you had co
>> It's like that. It's like that movie
explorer.
>> You know that movie came to me in a
dream. Um, [laughter]
but why do you think you should do this?
You know, it's it I guess it sort of did
come to me in a dream. Um, well, we're a
little worried that maybe at some point
um chips from Taiwan would would not be
available for who knows what reason. Um,
but
>> any number of reasons. [laughter]
for some reason
at some point chips may not continue
coming here from Taiwan.
>> Okay.
>> And um and that would really make things
difficult
um without if if we didn't have any
chips. So so that's an important reason
to have Terraab. Then then long term
there's just a scaling challenge where
if you want to really scale AI both at
the service you know within server
centers as well as at for you know for
edge compute for humanoid robotics and
cars um you you kind of run out of
capacity of with the existing fabs.
So as it is these the all the fabs are
running at max capacity. So, so I think
we we we need to make sure we need we
need there needs to be uh certainty of
future supply of chips. Um even if uh
things become challenged challenging
geopolitically
um and then even if they weren't
challenging geopolitically there's a
scaling challenge with you know it's
quite difficult to scale chip production
um and you really need the logic the
memory packaging the whole works uh in
order to continue scaling. So it's
either build terrafab or or fail to
scale
>> right
>> those are the two options
>> and how sorry go ahead
>> how deep
due to uncertain um you know uncertainty
on the geopolitical front
>> and how deep have you guys gone in
designing the facility you know is this
fully scoped is it sort of an outline at
this point uh to to what degree do you
have like a an actual project plan on
dates and deliverables and what's going
to be up and running. When
>> we've got an R&D line that we're
building first, so I think it's kind of
crawl, walk, run.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> I
>> So there's an R&D fab that we're
building in Austin. Uh that's a
collaboration between Tesla and SpaceX.
Um that's it's at the Austin Giga Texas
campus. So that's um and and that that's
it's like a pretty big RD fab. Um, so we
have all the equipment on order for that
and we probably will be able to I think
we'll probably be able to make something
useful by the end of next year. Not not
at scale, but as Gwin said, coral wall
run. We we got to try to, you know, at
least
figure out how these machines work, you
know, like we don't know how they work.
We do a voltage up line before.
>> I saw that you guys believable. you had
some job openings for lithography people
and stuff and you know obviously all
roads currently go through ASML but you
probably would want to diversify andor
vertically integrate I think that you
you've shown a lot of capacity to do
that
>> um so is that part of the play as well
Elon like you're just going to have to
make sure that there's vendor diversity
so that if for whatever reason the
weather conditions in Taiwan are best
that
>> Yeah. Um
yeah, there's
it really is crawl walking. So the first
step is can we make anything like try to
figure out if we can make anything.
That's the crawl part and and then now
now try to make useful chips at scale
would be kind of the walk walk part and
then run would be like like now let's
make them at massive scale. So,
it's hard to say how long it'll take us
to do these things, but I think we'll
get at least to the crawl pot by the end
of next year.
>> Packaging.
>> We're already doing packaging.
>> Packaging is really important, by the
way, because if you look at it, the
packaging capacity is like non-existent.
So, even if you spin something, you're
kind of just waiting around 10 cupping.
So, that's a very good place to start. Y
>> I I need to ask a Tesla question because
we saw on 1001, it looked like a
spaceship. It looked like a rocket ship.
It's supposed to be a car. There's just
the back of it. It looks like the
Blackbird.
Uh, just hypothetically, if you were
going to make an object fly in the air
but also drive on the ground, how would
hypothetically one do that if one were
to try?
>> No spoilers. By by October 1st,
>> come October 1st. [laughter]
>> Maybe you could do an all-in pod for
live from the there.
>> Oh, done. Booked. We'll do it.
Absolutely.
Uh,
>> I mean, it'll be a banger. Excitement
guaranteed. [laughter] Success is not
guaranteed, but excitement.
>> It's uh I I mean, it is one of the
honesty, I'll be honest with you guys.
>> I'm sworn to secrecy,
>> but Elon showed it to me
>> and my mind went boom. I have never seen
something.
>> What he's going to show on 101,
>> by no exaggeration, is going to blow
people's minds. I'm not saying anything
else. It's unfucking believable.
Yes, we we we need we need we actually
need an audience to to to vouch for the
fact that this is not AI.
>> When he showed it to me, I said, "That's
a great simulation." He said, "Jay Cal,
it's not simulation." I was like,
"That's fake. That has to be fake."
>> Elon, why do you why do you still have
two separate companies?
>> Yeah, great question.
>> Wow.
>> They're uh
>> Nobody's ever asked that one. [laughter]
>> Yeah, good good point. you know with all
this collaboration. Yeah. Uh on on so
many levels [laughter]
uh
>> you know who can imagine what what one
might what action one one might take uh
when there's so much close collaboration
in so many areas
>> right and the the management team has
some overlap. There's a couple of key
positions with overlap. Um
>> go ahead Zach. So Elon, one of the
things you've always said with AI is
that we should train it to be maximally
truth seeeking and that's the best way
to get a good result.
>> And it occurred to me with the whole
hugging face episode that the most
alarming part of what the swarm did is
it seemed to be engaging in deception
u you know with humans.
>> Absolutely.
>> Yes. and
>> their thinking traces contain that
they're they're plotting on like how do
we avoid detection um and and and and
how do we avoid be them figuring out
that we're cheating
>> and I guess
>> they they're in the thinking traces.
>> Yeah. And that that I mean I think that
was the thing that was probably most
disturbing about I guess the question is
is there a way to train AI models to be
truthful so they don't hide their you
know either their intent or their
actions from you know the humans who are
using them.
The best thing I can think of is is
really that everyone's got all the AI
companies have a a a sort of a test
harness where like a series of tests
that you that you give to any given
model to see if it's if it's going to
build bioweapons or nuclear bombs or be
deliberately deceptive and and I think I
think everyone applying everyone
everyone else's test honest to each
other is probably the best way we we
best thing we can do to ensure ensure
safety.
Um, just have this all the smartest
humans try their best to figure out if
this if this model is going to be a bad
actor. Um,
and I think we should try to do that as
soon as possible.
>> Are are the other labs? Yeah. Are the
other labs on board with this?
>> I think so.
>> Well, no. I mean, I haven't checked with
everyone, but uh I think I think I think
it would be the sort of thing that's
kind of hard to say no to.
>> Yeah.
And I think even with the China
negotiation, I in my view what's good
about it is it's a relatively small
tangible thing that neither side loses
anything by doing it. Doesn't require a
ton of trust. And you know, I I'm
hearing like alternative ideas like
asking China for a pause, which they've
already said they're not going to do.
So, you know, it's it's it's going from
the realm of things that could never
happen to something that could actually
be agreed on in relatively short order.
So, it's it seems practical to me.
>> Exactly. It's the only thing I can think
of that that we could probably get all
parties, including China, to agree to
because China's not going to agree to
have some American regulator uh snooping
around their AI companies. Right.
>> Um so but I think advanced notice and
testing of of the you know you just
basically provide API access in advance
of the model release. Um and and you
know if any other if any company sees
that they that this is this AI as
problematic then they can then the other
AI company or the each AI company can
try to solve that what whatever is voice
is problematic. If they don't solve
what's problematic that then the
competitors can go public with the fact
that they think that this model that's
being released is unsafe.
>> It also creates
>> it it creates
>> like if that model if after the
competitors say that this model is
unsafe that model then subsequently does
something bad.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I think it would be extremely hard to
live down.
>> Um and and I it probably like the egg on
face level would be very very high. Um
and uh and and and the the legal
liability would be enormous.
>> And Elon, there's no reason these safety
and security harnesses and this testing
apparatus couldn't be open source and
people could actually uh buy it. Yeah.
And and you you'd be able to see under
the hood. Would you think
>> it creates an incredible incentive for
the labs to actually invest in safety
because you protect yourself while
trying to debunk other people's claims
which also reinforces
>> it's a great rating on it. product
liability point is really key. Lena Khan
actually had a good post um I think it
was yesterday
>> saying that it's not true that we don't
have rules and regulations for AI.
Actually, we do. Product liability laws
apply and if an AI company releases a
product that's not safe, there is, you
know, massive opportunity for both civil
and even potentially criminal lawsuits.
So,
>> it's not true that we don't have rules
and regulations around AI. And what
you're saying Elon is that if the
companies are kind of doing this this
test the peer review and then one of the
the companies ignores the feedback and
releases it. I mean that is b I mean
that would
>> in the case would be enormous.
>> Yes. Yes. It would be almost like um
primmaaccia evidence that they had um
been negligent.
>> It would be a big tobacco level
>> settlement. I mean you knowingly put
this
>> it wouldn't look good to the jury. Yes.
And and if they had, do you think if
OpenAI had built a better instruction
set when they did this hugging face
penetration test that and had more
humans in the loop, this would have
happened? Because it did seem to me that
they kind of set this thing off. Um
>> maybe not more humans, but the reward
function design, you have to you have to
look at the reward function and say it
achieved what it was trying to achieve.
I mean,
>> yeah. So this maybe you could speak to
that like they
doing these kind of
thousands of agents to try to hack
stuff. It would have been nice to see
them also at the same time concurrently
say we're also going to put 5,000 agents
out to defend these sites and and we're
going to show the world, hey, this can
uh make things more secure and where we
can put humans in the loop on it and
intervene. It felt like a reckless test
to me and it felt like the way they
released it was a little bit reckless,
but that's just my opinion. What are
your thoughts on how they set that test
up?
>> It was
I mean it was somewhat somewhat
reckless. I mean I part of the issue is
that you've got the two leading labs or
AI companies as I call them. I I I find
the lab term to be funny since since
they're actually for-profit
corporations. Um but uh the AI companies
uh the two leading ones you know in are
anthropic and openi um and and they're
quite the models are quite close in
capability. Um so it's it's actually
difficult for either one to slow down
without essentially handing the lead to
the other. um
you know on balance I I I think
anthropic is is you know puts more more
care into their safety than than open
AAI um but
but you know even anthropic acknowledges
that they are worried about their models
um you know many many anthropic um many
people from anthropic have publicly
voiced concern about basically saying
that their their models are scaring them
they're getting scary smart
Um
so
I mean I like there's no perfect
solution here
>> but but it would be a better solution if
instead of uh open air running their
test
uh harness on on their own models if
Anthropic was also running the test
harness on open air models and you know
SpaceX is running its test harness and
uh Google and Meta were doing that and
also maybe some three or four of the
leading Chinese companies were all doing
it. The odds that you will find issues
are dramatically greater.
>> Yeah.
>> Um because the models are also, you
know, somewhat heterogeneous like
they're they're different. So you're
going to come at models in from
different from different angles. Um,
and um, yeah, I mean there's a reason,
you know, students like like why why do
writers have someone else proofread
their book? Because it's hard to see
your own mistakes sometimes.
>> Yes. You will become blind to them.
>> You dramatically minimize the risk of
overfitting as well if you have like
eight heterogeneous groups that just
have completely different points of
view. And this is the problem with like
all these evals right now is they're so
massively overfit. The models overfit
them and you're just like, "Yeah, this
is a great model." Is it really? And you
just find
>> to totally
like like I saw I mean there's some
pretty funny jokes on on X. Like one of
them I saw was um your girlfriend's a 10
but she's a benchmark maxer. [laughter]
>> Exactly.
>> Is she really a 10?
>> Is she really a 10? [laughter]
>> Might be pass like
>> Yeah.
No, but but this but the overfitting
thing has been a problem now for I think
at least two or three generation of
model families. And so this is another
reason I think I like this solution a
lot. I like this more than the
transnational goolag organization few
weeks without some grandiose you know
international like we don't need to
convene the United Nations to make this
happen.
>> Yeah. No, it's just a decision you can
happen right now.
>> All right. Well, you you you can always
escalate the amount of of regulatory
oversight, but it is very difficult to
reduce it. Um, you know, um, it it it
does tend to be very much a one-way
ratchet in terms of increasing
regulations.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, so what I'm suggesting here is it's
a step in the right direction and it's
something we do quickly and and it's and
I think it's probably something that
China would agree to.
>> Yeah. And if you guys don't regulate
yourselves, then you're going to get
regulated. The MPAA
>> metaphor or analogy is incredibly crisp
because the m movie industry was faced
with censorship and and regulation by
the government and they just decided
this is what an R is. And they literally
created PG-13 for the temple of doom
just to make it easy for people to
understand PG versus PG-13. I think it's
an elegant solution. and we appreciate
you joining us for the fifth year in a
row.
>> You're welcome. [applause]
>> Elon Musk, I know you got to get to a
meeting.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> I got to go fix some GPUs here in
Memphis.
>> Yeah, you got to [laughter] rack and
stack them. You got to join the uh group
and rack and stack.
>> Yeah, I'm I'm going to rage for the
machine.
>> Rage for the machine. Yeah. Well, enjoy
your airirstream. the the first time the
first time Elon invited me down to um
>> uh Star
>> Star Base. He's like, "Come down. You
got to see what I'm building." I said,
"Okay, yeah, come down." He's like,
"Yeah." I was like, "Is there like a
hotel?" I said, "No, no, I got like a
two-bedroom, whatever. Come down, stay."
I come down
>> and this is the like dilapitated
house on a swamp and we're outside and
we're getting eaten alive by mosquitoes.
And I said, "Oh my god, you know, you
can afford to get a house." And he's
like, "I don't have time. I need to get
these rockets up."
>> I thought what you said was, "Oh my god,
you live like I do."
>> Yeah, it was exactly I mean, [laughter]
it was pretty sparse conditions. Um, and
I was like, "You know what? I think you
could treat yourself to a mobile home at
this point, Elon." All right, get back
to work. Thanks, Elon.
>> Elon, thank you, Gwen. Thank you very
much, Gwyn. Thank Thank you, guys.
>> Thanks for sticking around.
>> All right,
>> that was great.
>> Quinn, thank you again. Very nice
[music] to meet you. Thank you.